A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Vice Presidential records, Foreign Affairs and National Security, Series 19 FA385
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Murphy Commission Background Volumes, 1973-1975
  - Book VIII, compiled March 17, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 400)
    Testimony from General Goodpaster and Secretary Rogers and review of draft report of Committee on Intelligence.
    Tab A - List of Recommendations by Chapter Tab B - Director Central Intelligence from Public Life Tab C - Greater Civilian Control over NSA Tab D - All SIGINT Under NDA Tab E - All Paramilitary Operations Under DOD Tab F - Presidential Certification of Covert Action Tab G - Amendment to Foreign Assistance Act Tab H - Oversight of Operational Activity Tab I - Commission Participants Tab J - Senator Muskie's Comments on Congress Concerning Aid for Turkey and Trade with the Soviet Union Tab K - "The Politics of Appeasement," Irving Kristol, Wall Street Journal Tab L - Portion of National Security Act Pertaining to CIA Tab M - Paper on Public Opinion Tab N - Draft Report on Intelligence I - Introduction II - Policy Making and Intelligence Support III - Resource Management and the Role of the DCI (Directory of Central Intelligence) IV - Defense Intelligence Activites V - The Clandestine Services and Covert Action VI - Declassification and Protection of Sources VII - Supervision and Oversight
  - Book X, compiled March 15, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 401)
    Additional information on March 17 meeting including Meeting Agenda, General Goodpaster's testimony and intelligence draft.
    Tab A - Marvin Gray memo on Draft Report on Intelligence Tab B - Comments on the Draft Murphy Commission Intelligence Report Tab C - Comments on Certain "Recommendations" of the Draft Report of Committee II Tab D - Summary Statement, Meeting November 1973, Intelligence (Colby, Porter State), Hall (DOD), De Poix (DIA), Schoning (DOD/ISA)
  - Attachments for Books 2-8, Economics (Box 19, Folder 402)
  - Attachments for Book X, Summaries of Testimony, June 1973-September 1974; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 403)
  - Attachments for Book X, Summaries of Testimony, June 1973-September 1974; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 404)
  - Book XI, compiled March 31, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 405)
    Agenda for Meeting of March 31, 1975. Testimony by former Secretary of STate Rogers and Secretary Simon. Discussion of the Survey of Congress conducted by the Commission.
    Tab A - Suggested Questions for Secretary Rogers Tab B - Suggested Questions for Secretary Simon Tab C - Summary Report of Results of Congressional Survey (Basic Overview) Tab D - List of Interview Proposals Tab E - Legislators Appraisals of Sixteen Foreign Policy Proposals Tab F - Tables Which Accompany Basic Report at Tab C Tab G - Soviet Statements Tab H - Expulsions of Soviet Intelligence Officers (KGB and GRU)
  - Book XII, compiled April 11, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 406)
    Committee papers on status of Committee work, "other projects," overall schedule, and draft of Economic Committee Report for April 21 meeting.
    Tab A - Letter from George Meany Tab B - Foreign Organizations Tab C - Other Projects Tab D - Draft Paper on Foreign Economic Policies Tab E - Council on International Economic Policy (CIEP) Tab F - Council on Economic Policy
  - Book XIV, compiled April 21, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 407)
    Agenda for April 21 and 22 Meetings. Presentation of Congressional Committee and National Security reports.
    Tab A - Comments by Senator Spong on Congressional Report Tab B - Senator Mansfield's Comments Tab C - Report of Congressional Committee Tab D - Wagner Comments on Televised Debates Tab E - Comparison of Congressional Survey Findings and Recommendations of the Committee on Congress and Congressional-Executive Relations Tab F - Comments on Second Draft of National Security Council Report
  - Book XVI, compiled April 20, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 408)
    Report of the National Security Subcommittee.
    Tab A - Comments on Recommendations Tab B - Comments on Recommendations by NSC Tab C - Comments on Recommendations by State Tab D - Comments on Recommendations by ACDA Tab E - Comments on Recommendations by OMB Tab F - Comments on Recommendations by DOD Tab G - Text of National Security Subcommittee Report
  - Book XVII, compiled April 28, 1975, Folder 1 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 409)
    Agenda for Meetings of April 28 and 29. Testimony on personnel issues, guidance in the intelligence area, and discussion of the Economic Committee Report.
    Tab A - Articles on Intelligence Tab B - Differences in the Casey and Volcker Drafts Tab C - Comments by the Vice President on an Earlier Economic Draft Tab D - The Casey Draft Tab E - The Volcker Draft Tab F - The McKitterick Alternative
  - Book XVII, compiled April 28, 1975, Folder 2 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 410)
  - Book XVIII, compiled May 12, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 411)
    Agenda for Meeting of May 12. State and White House organization issues. Report on public opinion and foreign policy.
    Sec 1 - State and White House Organization Sec 2 - Public Opinion and Foreign Policy Sec 3 - Agenda for Remainder of Murphy Commission Sessions Sec 4 - Executive Agreements and Executive Privilege
    Tab A - Research Paper - Organizing the State Department and the White House Tab B - State Department Chart (Current) Tab C - State Department (Proposed) Tab D - Criteria Rating Chart Tab E - L. William Seidman Memo - Economic Policy Organization Tab F - Maxwell Taylor Article in "Orbis" Tab G - Public Opinion and Foreign Policy Tab H - Dr. Wagner Submission on use of T.V. Tab I - Public Opinion and the Use of Force Tab J - Agenda of Commission Meetings for May and June Tab K - William Spong Memo on Executive Agreements and Executive Privilege Tab L - Statement of G. H. Hackworth on Executive Agreements Tab M - Speech by Attorney General E. H. Levi Tab N - List of Commissioners
  - Book XIX, compiled May 16, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 412)
    Agenda for next meetings. Outgrowths from last meeting. Activities of other Commissioners. Executive Agreements and Executive Privilege. Stanton Committee Report.
    Tab A - Report of May 12 Murphy Commission Meeting Tab B - Comments of Congressman Broomfield Tab C - Dr. Wagner's Comments on the Working Hypothesis of the Commission Tab D - Comments on Stanton Report by USIA Directory
  - Book XX, compiled May 19, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 413)
    Agenda for Meeting of May 19. Topics for discussion included personnel, policy planning, and multilateral diplomacy.
    Encl 1 - Personnel Encl 2 - Policy Planning Encl 3 - Multilateral Diplomacy
    Tab A - Summary of Personnel Paper Tab B - Draft Section for Final Report on Policy Planning Tab C - Draft Section on Multilateral Diplomacy
  - Book XXI, compiled May 20, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 414)
    Agenda for Meeting of May 20. Discussion of draft on Intelligence, Policy Planning and Multilateral Diplomacy.
    Tab A - Draft on Intelligence.
  - Book XXII, compiled May 23, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 415)
    Agenda for May 27 and 28 meetings. Topics include Multilateral Diplomacy, Secretary Schlesinger testimony, Humanitarian Issues, Public Diplomacy, Overseas Posts and Missions, Budgets and State Department Organization.
    Tab A - Commission Letter to Secretary Schlesinger Tab B - Draft on Public Diplomacy
  - Book XXIII, compiled May 27, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 416)
    Agenda for May 27 meeting. Discussion of multilateral diplomacy, intelligence, humanitarianism and public diplomacy.
    Tab A - Memorandum for the Vice President (Basic memo from Book 22) Tab A1 - Multilateral Diplomacy and Global Issues Tab B - Human Rights, Humanitarian, and Ethical Considerations in the Conduct of Foreign Policy Tab C - U.S. Policies on Human Rights and Authoritarian Regimes Tab D - Public Diplomacy Tab E - Stanton Panel on USIA Tab F - A Critique of the Stanton Report on Information, Education and Cultural Relations Tab G - Abbott Washburn comments on Stanton Panel Recommendations Tab H - George Meany letter on USIA Tab I - Statement of Director, USIA before Committee on Foreign Relations, U.S. Senate Tab J - Statement of Frank Stanton before Senate Foreign Relations Committee
  - Book XXV, compiled June 3, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 417)
    Agenda for June 3 meeting. Discussion of Intelligence and White House Organizations.
    Tab A - Memorandum for the Vice President on May 27 meeting. Tab B - Intelligence Issues Requiring Commission Decision Tab C - Commission Discussion of "Central Structure for Policy Integration" Tab D - State Department and White House Organization Tab E - Alternative Patterns of White House Organization Tab F - Outline of Commission's Final Report Tab G - Executive Agreements and Executive Privilege Tab H - Draft Vice Presidential letter to Commissioner Murphy on Executive Agreements and Executive Privilege Tab I - Murphy memo for Commissioners on Intelligence and White House
  - Book XXVI, compiled June 2, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 418)
    Additional items for June 3 meeting. Casey views on White House Organization and Casey and Murphy views on Intelligence. Wallison argument against Creation of a Separate Director of National Intelligence. Draft of Dissenting Report.
    Tab A - Agenda for June 3 Meeting Tab B - Organization for Foreign Affairs Tab C - Murphy Memo on Intelligence Tab C1 - Murphy Memo on White House Organization Tab D - Wallison Memo on Murphy Commission (National Intelligence) Tab E - Dissenting Opinion
  - Book XXVII, compiled June 14, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 419)
    Report on previous meeting. Topics discussed were Executive-Congressional Relations, White House Economic Structure, and Stanton Recommendations Concerning USIA.
    Tab A - Executive-Congressional Relations Tab B - Attorney General Levi letter to Vice President on Executive Privilege and Executive Agreements Tab C - Discussion Paper on Organizing for Foreign Economic Policy Tab D - Draft Commission Report on USIA and VOA (Broomfield comments) Tab E - Draft Supplementary Opinion
  - Book XXVIII, compiled July 11, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 420)
    Press Reports and Follow-up Editorials.
    Tab A - "The Washington Post" article of June 29, 1975 Tab B - "The New York Times" article of June 29, 1975 Tab C - "Washington Star" article of June 29, 1975 Tab D - "Baltimore Sun" article of June 29, 1975 Tab E - "The Christian Science Monitor" article of July 1, 1975 Tab F - "The Washington Post" article of July 7, 1975 Tab G - "Washington Star" editorial of July 1, 1975 Tab H - "Norfolk Ledger-Star" article of July 12, 1975 Tab I - Commission Press Release of June 27, 1975 Tab J - Rumsfeld memos on Commission Report
  - Background Workbook #1, October 1974; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 421)
  - Background Workbook #1, October 1974; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 422)
  - Background Workbook #2, Memoranda, 1973-1974 (Box 21, Folder 423)
  - Background Workbook #3, Meeting Minutes, May 1973-September 1974 (Box 21, Folder 424)
  - Background Workbook #4, Background Papers, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 425)
  - Background Workbook #5, Intelligence, 1973-1974 (Box 21, Folder 426)
  - Background Workbook #6, National Security, 1973-1974 (Box 21, Folder 427)
  - Background Workbook #7, International Economics, 1973-1974 (Box 21, Folder 428)
  - Background Workbook #9, Public Diplomacy and Support, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 429)
- National Center for Productivity and Quality of Life, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 430)
  Draft of "Program for Achieving a More Productive Regulatory System," April 16, 1976. Includes NAR's handwritten edits.